Guide to the John B. Bender Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
John B. Bender papers
1966-2004
SC0577
Bender, John B.
20.5 Linear feet (35 boxes)
These papers pertain to Bender's teaching and writing. Included are correspondence; research files; departmental files pertaining to comparative literature at Stanford; lectures and talks; publication files containing correspondence, drafts of articles, and proofs; class files (primarily on Shakespeare and Spenser) containing syllabi, reading lists, lecture notes, class handouts, and other materials; and drafts of his book IMAGINING THE PENITENTIARY.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
The papers were given to the Stanford University Archives by John B. Bender in 1999 and 2005, and 2006.
Information about Access
Files in Accession ARCH-2005-088, Subseries 6 are restricted. The collection is otherwise open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
John Bryant Bender earned his A.B. in English at Princeton University in 1962 and his Ph.D. at Cornell University in 1967. He has been a professor of English at Stanford University since 1967. His publications include SPENSER AND LITERARY PICTORIALISM (1972); IMAGINING THE PENITENTIARY: FICTION AND THE ARCHITECTURE OF MIND IN EIGHTEENTH-CENTURY ENGLAND (1987); and CHRONOTYPES: THE CONSTRUCTION OF TIME (1991), which he edited with David E. Wellbery.
Description of the Collection
These papers pertain to Bender's teaching and writing. Included are correspondence; research files; departmental files pertaining to comparative literature at Stanford; lectures and talks; publication files containing correspondence, drafts of articles, and proofs; class files (primarily on Shakespeare and Spenser) containing syllabi, reading lists, lecture notes, class handouts, and other materials; and drafts of his book IMAGINING THE PENITENTIARY.
Access Terms
Bender, John B.; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616; Spenser, Edmund, 1552?-1599--Study and teaching.; Stanford University. Department of English. Faculty.; English literature--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-1999-266
  - Correspondence, 1967-1974 Jun (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1974 Jul-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Pictorialism - Notes for Book (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - MLA Talk - Final Manuscript and Last Revision (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Humanities 192 - Renaissance Florence and Michelangelo (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Humanities 192 - The Arts and the Humanities - Syllabus, Reserve, Bibliography, Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Western Culture, 1980 winter (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - English 314B - Bender and Rebholz, 1974 spring (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - English 234 - French and Italian Renaissance Poetry- France, 1971 summer (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - English 314 - Drama and Society in Renaissance England, 1979 winter (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - English 314 - Drama and Society in Renaissance England, 1979 winter (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - CIV- Handouts, Info Sheets, Class Lists, and Syllabus (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Materials on English 182 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - English 182 - Lecture outlines - France, 1971 spring (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - English 77- Lecture outlines - France, 1971 spring (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Elizabethan and Jacobean Drama (160-C) (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
  - Danforth Seminar (with David Riggs), 1971 Jun (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - English 302 - Spenser and Shakespeare, 1982, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
  - English 172B - Spenser and Milton (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - English 314C - Spenser and the Renaissance (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Faerie Queen, Book III: Teaching Notes (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Spenser Society, Presentation with S.K. Heniger, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - English 272 - Spenser and his contemporaries: Syllabus, Reserve List (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Stencil of Quotation on Spenser from Seven Types of Ambiguity (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - J.W. Bennet "Britain Among the Fortunate Isles," SP, 53, 114-140, Abstract and Stencil, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Tasso's Account of the Allegory of the Poem (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Introductory Lecture on Spenser (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Ants Oras - "Spenser and Milton: Some Parallels and Contrasts in the Handling of Sound" (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "The Tempest at Court," "The Day of the Tempest," and "The Tempest and the Court Masque Reconsidered" (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - The Tempest: JBB Writings (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Clark Library/NCLA/USC Conference- "Shakespeare's Renaissance", 1981 Nov (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Affinities between Jacobean Masques and Plays (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - "The Day of the Tempest" talk for Berkeley and Huntington, clean typescript and copy (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Pamphlets (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - The Tempest: Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Silenus (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Witchcraft and Magic (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - All Saints Day - Scriptures (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Prudence (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - The Tempest - Reading Notes on Masque Project (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Hallowmas notes - winter (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - The Tempest - Ideas and Leads (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - English 173 - Shakespeare General Preparation and Background (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Rose Theatre, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Shakespeare at Cliveden, 1978-1980 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Shakespeare, 1982 summer (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Cliveden, 1980 fall (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Shakespeare 25 - Syllabus, Chronology, Exams, 1968-1969, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Shakespeare and Renaissance Tragedy - English 160/260A, 1988 summer (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Shakespeare at Cliveden, 1975 spring (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Seminar on the Tempest (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - English 273 - Advanced Shakespeare (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - English 373 - Twelfth Night, Measure for Measure, Tempest, 1981 winter (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Shakespeare Handouts (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Shakespeare Films (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Shakespeare - Sources of Pictures of His Age (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Shakespeare Bibliographic (from Ovid Riggs) (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Ideas of History in Shakespeare's England (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Images of Shakespeare's England: Slide Lecture (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Shakespeare and his theatre (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Macbeth: three lectures (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Macbeth: reading notes (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Hamlet: reading and discussion notes (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Hamlet: five lectures (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Othello: three lectures, 1980 Dec (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Othello: reading and discussion notes (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Richard II: reading and discussion notes (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Richard II: two lectures (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Richard III (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Henry V (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Henry IV: reading and discussion notes (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Form and Falstaff in I Henry IV (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - I Henry IV: first lecture (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Merchant of Venice (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - As You Like It Lecture and two Cliveden lectures (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - As You Like It: reading notes and student essay (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Romeo and Juliet (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Romeo and Juliet: notes (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Twelfth Night (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Measure for Measure (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - King Lear (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - King Lear: notes (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Antony and Cleopatra: notes for lecture discussion preceding second paper (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Antony and Cleopatra (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Coriolanus: two lectures (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Coriolanus: notes (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Pericles: notes (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The Winter's Tale: notes (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Shakespeare's Drama and the Winter's Tale (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Cymbeline: notes (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - The Tempest: two lectures (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - The Tempest: notes (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Shakespeare's late plays (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Introduction to Tom Jones: notes (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Introduction to Tom Jones: proofs and typescript (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous materials (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Prison Book - photocopied articles (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Comments from readers on Prison Book (including department comments and Chicago readings for final revision) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Preface - The Novel and the Rise of the Penitentiary (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Prison Project - Ideas and Leads (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Notes and materials relevant to Chapters I and VII and including early drafts (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
  - Prison Book - Introduction (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Prison Book - Chapter 1 notes, drafts, photocopies (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Prison Book - Introduction, notes, and readers' comments on early drafts (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Photocopy of Oglethorpe Reports on Prisons (extra copy) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Milan Prisons (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Howard, John - The State of the Prisons, photocopy of Everyman Ed. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Appendix - Report on Marshalsea and Fleet prisons (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Prisons in Literature and Art- Reading Notes (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Misc. from old "Newgate/Sublime" shelf - Executions (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Godwin, Williams- "Caleb Williams" article (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - English 264 - Enlightenment Ideas of Prison- Stanford 1977, Cliveden 1978 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Notes entered in bk7nts.txt (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Prison Book- Defoe Chapter (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Prison Book- Smollett (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Prison Book- Hogarth (see also Gay and Fielding) (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Prison Book- Gay (see also Hogarth and Fielding) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Prison Book- Fielding and Richardson (see also Gay and Hogarth) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Piranesi (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2005-088
  - Correspondence, Notes, and Miscellaneous Papers, Subseries 1
    - Bio/Biographical information (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Letters received, 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence [miscellaneous], 2001-2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Adams, Robert, correspondence, 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Darton, Robert, correspondence, 1992, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Journal of Aesthetics and Art Criticism, correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Sontag, Susan, correspondence, 1996, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Eng. 254 (D. Gigante's class), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Notes, origin of the novel, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Notes on Ian Duncan, "The Scottish Enlightenment and the Theory of Fiction", 2002 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Notes from workshop on "Emergence", 2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Notes on writing (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Scaglione Prize - MLA, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Stanford University Departmental Files and Personal Professional Files, Subseries 2
    - Comparative Literature departmentalization, 1985-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Comp Lit/MTL negotiations, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Gillespie, G., memo re comp lit, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Perloff, M., re comp lit, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Comp Lit: "Appointments: An Informal Guide", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Comp Lit review report, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Long range planning, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Rutgers position, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Berkeley 18th-century position, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Maryland visit and offer, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Future shock [re library position?] (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Stanford/Maryland [re talk and possible offer], 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Stanford/UCLA [re talk and possible offer], 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Stanford/UCLA correspondence [re talk and possible offer], 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Overseas Study Teaching Application, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Overseas Studies teaching application, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Conference Files and Other Professional Papers, Subseries 3
    Files in this subseries are arranged chronologically.
    - MLA talk, "A Theory of Literary Pictorialism", 1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Bender, "A Mode of Pictorialism in Spenser and Keats" with correspondence, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Fourth International Congress on the Enlightenment, paper ("Terror and Caprice in some Eighteenth-Century Images of Prison") and correspondence, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Fourth International Congress on the Enlightenment, program, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - English Institute, "Prison and the Architecture of Mind, a Study in Eighteenth-Century Aesthetics", 1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Bender, "Prison and the Architecture of Mind: A Study in Eighteenth-Century Aesthetics," Conference on British Studies, 1976 Apr (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - ASECS, Victoria, 1977 May (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Bender, "The Prison as Environment: A Study in Eighteenth-Century Aesthetics," ASECS, 1977 May (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Yale Conference, 1978 Oct (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Cal Tech lecture, "The Novel and the Rise of the Penitentiary", 1981 Dec (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - WSECS, seminar paper, "The Form of Reform: Narrative and the Penitentiary Idea", 1982 Apr (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - MLA, Bender's "The Novel and the Rise of the Penitentiary", 1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - MLA, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Bender, "Bentham's Narrative Systems", 1984 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - MLA, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Humanities Center, presentation on Imagining the Penitentiary, 1986 Feb (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Rutgers talk, "The Form of Reform: Narrative and the Penitentiary Idea in Eighteenth-Century England", 1987 Apr (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Bender, "Imagining the Penitentiary", 1987 Nov (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - ASECS, Knoxville, 1988 Apr (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - British Society for 18th Century Studies, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - WSECS [Western Society for 18th Century Studies], Berkeley, 1989 Feb (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Chicago, seminar on imaging the past, 1989 Apr (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - ASECS, New Orleans, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - NW ASECS, Seattle, 1989 Oct (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Canadian Society for 18th Century Studies, 1989 Oct (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Division of Knowledge Colloquium [Stanford University], 1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Abelove, Henry, reprint, "Some Speculations on the History of Sexual Intercourse during the Long Eighteenth Century in England", 1989 fall (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Australia, Humanities Research Center, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 10-12)
    - ASECS, Minneapolis, panel with Lennard Davis, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Harvard lecture, correspondence re, 1990 Nov (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Writing/Ecriture/Schrift Conference, 1991 Nov (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Goethe Institute, 1991 Sep (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Grumbecht / Lenoir, seminar in recording, 1991 Nov (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - ASECS Panel, Seattle, "Novelistic Technique and Cultural Formation, 1760-1820", 1992 Mar (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Art/Music/Literature Colloquium, 1992 Jul (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - UCLA, Clark Center, "Constructing the Body", 1992 Oct (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - NE ASECS (and lectures at Penn., Princeton, and Yale), 1992 Oct (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - MLA panel, "Medical Science and 18th Century Literature", 1992 Dec (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - U.S. News and World Report, college ratings, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Simultaneity Colloquium, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - ASECS (American Society for Eighteenth Century Studies), Providence, RI, 1993 Apr (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - NE ASECS, Yale, 1993 Oct (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Forschungsschwerpunkt miscellaneous, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - New Zealand Visit, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Berlin visit and SER collaboration with Berlin group, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - ASECS, Charleston, 1994 Mar (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Berkeley Medical History Seminar, 1994 Apr (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Cambridge University conference, "Unofficial Knowledge", 1994 Jun (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Berlin conference, closing remarks, 1994 Sep (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Dorrit Cohn's "Imagining the Penitentiary" and Bender's reply, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - ASECS, Tucson, 1995 Apr (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Copenhagen Seminar, "New Historicism", 1995 Jun (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - MW [Midwest] ASECS, Minneapolis, 1995 Oct (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - ASECS, Austin, 1996 Mar (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Clark Library conference, 1996 Jun (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - GEMCS [Group for Early Modern Cultural Studies], 1996 Sep (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - WSECS [Western Society for Eighteenth Century Studies] Panel, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Morocco invitation, 1995-1997 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Princeton conference, "Narrative Encounters", 1996 Oct (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Paris conferences (Crime et Chatiment dans la Grande-Bretagne du XVIIIe siecle), 1996, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - ASECS - Hume/Sympathy Panel [Nashville1997], 1996 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - ASECS, Nashville, 1997 Apr (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Walpole Conference, 1997 Jul (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Hogarth Symposium, Berkeley Art Museum (1998), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Lewis Foundation Panel (March 1998), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - New York University, 1998 Jan (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Warwick Conference, Sheffield, Cambridge, 1998 Feb (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Calgary, 1998 Feb (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Chicago Seminar, 1998 Nov (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - MLA, San Francisco arrangements, 1998 Dec (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Paris conference (L'aventure dans la Grande-Bretagne du XVIIIe siecle) and German lectures, 1998 Dec (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Humanities Center, fellows' end of year report, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Bender, "Science and Pornography", 1998 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Jameson [Presidential Lecture] and Bender's introduction, 1999 Jan (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Committee on Libraries, 1999 Mar (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - International Society for 18th Century Studies, Dublin, 1999 Jul (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Stanford University Libraries Dedication, 1999 Dec (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - ASECS Panel, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Boston University, lecture, 2000 Apr (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Remapping the Rise of the European Novel 1500-1800 (articles and typescripts by various authors), 2000-2001 and undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - International Society for 18th Century Studies, 2001-2003 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - ASECS, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - MLA, New York, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Grant Files, Subseries 4
    - ACLS application, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - CASBS application, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Grant applications for, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Guggenheim application, 1981 Sep (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - NEH Summer Stipend application, 1976-1982 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - NEH Summer Stipend, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - NEH Sr. Grant Application, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - NEH Sr. Grant Application, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - NEH Sr. Grant Application, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - NEH Stipend Grant application, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Research at Huntington Library, 1969-1981 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - "Seed Money" proposal, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Stanford Humanities Center grant applications, 1982, 1988-89 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Stanford Humanities Center applications, 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Publication Files, Subseries 5
    - Syracuse lecture (Vision and Textuality), 1989 Mar (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Princeton University Press, correspondence re Spenser and Literary Pictorialism, 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Reviews of Bender's Spenser and Literary Pictorialism, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Chronotypes, conference and published volume, 1990-1996 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Chronotypes, conference and published volume, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Gottschalk prize (for Imagining the Penitentiary), 1987 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Goldsmith essay - manuscript, proofs, notes, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Goldsmith essay, correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The Columbia History of the British Novel, correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Essay for Redrawing the Boundaries, with correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Joe Frank Festschrift (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Writing/Ecriture/Schrift - German translation of Bender's article (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Godwin essay for Watt Festschrift, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - "A New History of the Enlightenment," talk version and manuscript, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - "New Historicism," Notre Dame, 1988 Nov (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - SLR 1984 Prison/Novel article - permissions and copyright, 1983-1997 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Damrosch (The Profession of Eighteenth-Century Literature) project, 1987-1992 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Prison book - acknowledgement and gift copies (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - "The Day of the Tempest," manuscript and correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Responses to "The Day of the Tempest", 1980-1982 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Pattern Poetry by Dick Higgins - TLS review, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "Piranesi Show at the Hayward Gallery" - typescript and TLS publication, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Eccentric Spaces by Harbison, review of - typescript and TLS publication, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Review of three Piranesi books – typescript and TLS publication, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - The Analogy of the Faerie Queene by Nohrnberg, review of - typescript and TLS publication, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - The Renaissance Imagination by Gordon, review of - typescript and TLS publication, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Mirror and Veil by O'Connell, review of, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Jonson's Gypsies Unmasked by Randall, review of, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - The Romantic Prison by Brombert, review of, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - The Renaissance and the Gods, review of, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Form and Transformation in Music and Poetry of the English Renaissance by Johnson, review of, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - The Grotesque: A Study in Meaning by Barasch, review of, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Poetic Closure by Smith, review of, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Austen review, TLS, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Turned to Account by Faller, review of, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - The Wife of Martin Guerre by Lewis, review of, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Spenser Encyclopedia, "Narrative" - text and correspondence, 1984-1988 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Spenser Encyclopedia, "Narrative" - secondary sources (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Spenser Encyclopedia, "Pictorialism", 1984-1986 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Imagining the Penitentiary – notes and correspondence on production and editing, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 1)